Guide to the History of Medicine artifacts collection, 1550-1980s RL.10155
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Bernard F. Fetter Collection Artifacts, 20th century, approx. 30 items
  - Pocket hypodermic needle kit, early 20th century (Artifact-box 304, Item hfette0001)
    Pocket hypodermic needle kit. Rounded metal case.
    Received from: Bernard F Fetter, MD
  - Air-inflated pessary, undated (Artifact-box 34, Item hfette0003)
    Marked with Providence, RI: Davol Rubber Co., size 4.
  - Collection of medical instruments, mid-20th century (Artifact-box 27, Item hfette0005, Artifact-box 28, Artifact-box 29)
    Consists of instruments from the respective medical practices of the Drs. Fetter: uterine dilator, square hemometer tube, Eisenstein ecto-endo cervical scraper, hypodermic syringe, glass jars, brass colored hook for excising tumors, metal basin, stethoscope, dressing forceps, obstetrical forceps, cyrtometer, post-nasal forceps, tenaculum forceps, clamp with handle, speculum, diagnostic aesthesiometric, percussor, rubber air bag and metal tube.
    Received from: Bernard F. Fetter, MD; William J. Fetter, MD
  - Electrocautery set, mid-20th century (Artifact-box 33, Item hfette0006)
    Transformer in walnut housing with pistol, cautery tips, and gyn-a-lite. Marked with Elmhurst, NY: National Electric Instrument Co. Model no. 900.
  - Diaphragm chestpieces for Fleischer stethoscope, mid-20th century (Artifact-box 237, Item hfette0007)
    Three diaphragm chestpieces, marked Rutherford, NJ: Becton Dickinson & Co. Housed in two soft pouches.
  - Squibb urinometer, undated (Artifact-box 232, Item hfette0008)
    Rochester, NY: Will Corporation. Housed in original packaging.
  - Sprague Rappaport type stethoscope, mid-20th century (Artifact-box 239, Item hfette0013)
    Sprague Rappaport type stethoscope. St. Petersburg, FL: BMS Model SR-2 in original box.
- Wilton G. Fritz Collection Artifacts, early to mid-20th century, approx. 36 items
  Artifacts donated by Wilton G. Fritz, MD.
  - Simpson obstetric forceps, early 20th century? (Artifact-box 26, Item hfritz0001)
    One forceps, made of stainless steel. Used by Dr. Fritz's father in his medical practice.
    Received from: Wilton G. Fritz, MD
  - Obstetrics and gynecology instruments, mid-20th century (Artifact-box 24, Item hfritz0002, Artifact-box 25)
    Approximately 35 instruments, including forceps, made of stainless steel. Used by Dr. Fritz (Duke, 1944) in his medical practice.
- Eleanor B. Hall Collection Artifacts, undated, 10 items
  Artifacts donated by Eleanor B. Hall.
  - Nine cupping glasses with knobs, undated (Artifact-box 156, Item hhalle0001)
    Collection of cupping glasses from unknown source, with waxed wicking and cone wick. Cone wick was made by Mrs. Hall in the manner she had seen it used.
    Received from: Eleanor B. Hall
- J. Samuel Hammond Collection Artifacts, Mid-19th century to early 20th century, 9 items
  Artifacts donated by J. Samuel Hammond.
  - Kaz electric vaporizer, 1950s? (Artifact-box 374, Item hhammo0001)
    New York: Kaz Manufacturing Co. Vaporizer with original box, instructions & medication.
    Received from: J. Samuel Hammond
  - Three pairs of spectacles/eyeglasses, 19th-20th centuries (Artifact-box 201, Item hhammo0002)
    American spectacles include: 1. Small oval lens with wire frame. Mid 19th century or early 20th century [Webster County, Georgia ?]; in black case with cleaning cloth 2. Octagonal lens, no frame, gold wire legs. Early 20th century. [Americus, Georgia?] 3. Round lens with gold wire frame, plastic covered legs. Early 20th century [Americus, Georgia?].
- Ellis Herndon Hudson Collection Artifacts, 1952, 97 items
  Artifacts donated by Ellis Herndon Hudson.
  - Glass slide illustrations for Ellis Herndon Hudson's book on bejel, 1952 (Artifact-box 371, Item hhudso0001)
    Housed in two wooden boxes: Box 1 - 46 slides, Box 2 - 51 slides. The wooden boxes are marked with the date 1952.
    Illustrations for his book, Non-venereal syphilis; a sociological and medical study of bejel. (1958)
    Received from: Ellis Herndon Hudson
- D. Frank Hinnant Collection Artifacts, approximately 1917 and undated, 6 items
  Artifacts donated by D. Frank Hinnant.
  - Asafoetida amulet, approximately 1917 (Artifact-box 130, Item hhinna0001)
    Asafoetida amulet for child who died in 1917.
    Received from: D. Frank Hinnant
  - Glass pharmaceutical bottles, including asafoetida, undated (Artifact-box 134, Item hhinna0002)
    Five bottles, some with original contents.
- Charlotte S. Holt Collection Artifacts, 1961 and undated, 53 items
  Artifacts donated by The Estate of Charlotte S. Holt.
  - Bas-relief sculpture of infant in breech, 1961 (Box 93, Item hholtc0001)
    Plaster bas-relief by Holt. "G35" inscribed on reverse. Holt was a medical illustrator. Originally part of an exhibit she created with Dr. Frederick H. Falls for the Illinois State Department of Public Health.
    Received from: The Estate of Charlotte S. Holt
  - Obstetrical forceps and model baby heads, undated (Artifact-box 5, Item hholtc0002, Artifact-box 6)
    Obstetrical forceps and model baby heads created by Holt. Three sets of rubber heads with forceps. Salvaged from a damaged display.
  - Bas-relief sculpture of infant, 1961 (Artifact-box 345, Item hholtc0003)
    Demonstrates fetal fractures of skull and clavicle. Created by Holt from plaster, hand-colored. "#45 OB-Forceps Ex." on reverse of sculpture. Originally part of an exhibit created with Dr. Frederick H. Falls for the Illinois State Department of Public Health.
  - Original exhibit drawings, approximately 1961 (Box 84, Item hholtc0004)
    Drawings are of fetuses in utero and obstetrical techniques, hand-drawn by illustrator Charlotte Holt for an exhibit, likely the same as described in the other entries for the Holt artifacts collection. Accompanied by large exhibit caption cards. No online image.
- Elizabeth Kellogg Collection Artifacts, 1930s-1940s, 1 items
  Artifacts donated by Elizabeth Kellogg.
  - Bausch & Lomb microscope, 1930s-1940s (Artifact-box 129, Item hkello0001)
    Inscription reads "Med. Dept. U.S. Army." Made of black cast iron.
    Received from: Elizabeth Kellogg
- Henry E. Kolbe Collection Artifacts, 1912, 1 items
  Artifacts donated by Henry E. Kolbe.
  - Silver suture ring, 1912 (Artifact-box 35, Item hkolbe0001)
    Silver ring made from surgical sutures.
    Mary R. Kolbe, had the ring made from silver sutures used to close her surgical incision. The surgeon was Dr. Joseph Colt Bloodgood of Baltimore.
    Received from: Henry E. Kolbe
- Dr. Wallace W. Lindahl Collection Artifacts, 1840s-1960s, approx. 30 items
  Artifacts donated by Dr. Wallace W. Lindahl, MD.
  - Cupping set, 19th century (Artifact-box 82, Item hlinda0001)
    Made in England. Consists of a set of glass cups with brass aspirating syringe in velvet-lined mahogany case.
    Received from: Dr. Wallace W. Lindahl, MD
  - Medical instruments, chiefly 20th century (Artifact-box 154, Item hlinda0002, Box 75)
    Velcro model. Obstetric forceps, vaginal speculum, dilators, ice box, stethoscope, two pieces of large laboratory glass
  - Small pharmaceutical kit in leather bag, undated (Artifact-box 186, Item hlinda0003)
    Small pharmaceutical kit in leather bag with handle. One of the end the bag has stitching torn loose. Includes glass vials, most with contents intact.
  - Homeopathic bag, 1840s-1880s (Artifact-box 161, Item hlinda0004)
    Homeopathic bag. St. Louis: A. S. Aloe & Co. Glass vials with cork stoppers. Contents intact. Leather box with metal fittings - handles missing. Name engraved of silver plate on cover: Dr. E.L. Smith.
  - Black zippered doctor's bag, undated (Artifact-box 207, Item hlinda0005)
    Black zippered doctor's bag. Contents include: Taylor's reflex hammer with rubber head & four glass thermometers of different styles.
  - Medicine case with medications in ampules, undated (Artifact-box 54, Item hlinda0006)
    Small leather medicine case with various medications in one or two cc single use ampules. Part of the contents of doctor's obstetrical bag (Acc # HLINDA0011).
  - Sims' speculum with duck bill blades, undated (Artifact-box 56, Item hlinda0007)
    Part of contents of doctor's obstetrical bag (Acc # HLINDA0011).
  - Brinkerhoff anal speculum with sliding blade, undated (Artifact-box 55, Item hlinda0008)
    Part of the contents of doctor's obstetrical bag (Acc # HLINDA0011).
  - Blunt hook and crochet for obstetrical use, undated (Artifact-box 198, Item hlinda0009)
    Blunt hook and crochet for obstetrical use. Part of the contents of doctor's obstetrical bag (Acc # HLINDA0011).
  - Dr. Young's perfection self-retaining rectal dilators, undated (Artifact-box 57, Item hlinda0010)
    Chicago: F.E. Young & Co. Four dilators in box with instructions. Part of the contents of doctor's obstetrical bag (Acc # HLINDA0011).
  - Doctor's obstetrical bag, late 19th-early 20th century (Artifact-box 73, Item hlinda0011)
    Leather bag (damaged). Contents include: four empty glass stoppered bottles, blunt hook and crochet, canula, Sims' speculum with duck bill blades, Brinkerhoff anal speculum, rectal dilators, hypodermic kit in leather box, stethoscope and blood pressure cuff. Items have individual records; see above.
  - Blood pressure cuff, 1960s (Artifact-box 151, Item hlinda0002)
    Sphygmomanometer and blood pressure cuff, 1960s.
- Caroline B. Long Collection Artifacts, undated, approx. 10 items
  Artifacts donated by Caroline B. Long.
  - Boston-style doctor's bag, undated (Artifact-box 375, Item hlongc0001, Artifact-box 376)
    Black leather bag containing assorted medical instruments.
    Received from: Caroline B. Long
- Robert Machemer Collection Artifacts, mid-20th century, 9 items
  Artifacts donated by Robert Machemer, MD.
  - Erisophake, mid-20th century (Artifact-box 295, Item hmachm0001)
    Marked V. Mueller & Co., USA. Includes handle with eight interchangeable cups.
    Used for removal of cataractous lens until the 1960s. Invented in 1917 by Ignacio Barraquer and improved in 1948 by A. E. Bell. The little cup was applied to the surface of the lens, suction was applied, then the cup with the adherent lens pulled out of the eye through a large corneal opening.
    Received from: Robert Machemer, MD
- Philip G. Maples Collection Artifacts, circa 1944-1947, 1 items
  Artifacts donated by Philip G. Maples.
  - Nurse apron, circa 1944-1947 (Artifact-box 240, Item hmaple0001)
    Student nurse fabric apron with five pearl stud buttons.
    Received from: Philip G. Maples
- Steven McCoy Collection Artifacts, approximately 1940s
  - Arlington Chemical Company (Yonkers, N.Y.) allergy test kit, from Watts Hospital, Durham, N.C., approximately 1930s (Box 379)
    Scope and Contents
    Dr. McCoy was a resident at Watts Hospital in Durham, N.C., and acquired this kit the year the hospital closed (1976). A piece of tape affixed to the lid of the kit appears to have "Dr. B.W. Roberts" written in faded ink. Dr. Roberts was a pediatrician at Watts Hospital in 1938.
- Prof. J. Horst Meyer Collection Artifacts, early 20th century, 1 items
  Artifacts donated by Prof. J. Horst Meyer, DSC.
  - "Styptic" case, early 20th century (Artifact-box 289, Item hmeyeh0001)
    Tin styptic case; on the lid is the name of Prof. Dr. Hans Horst Meyer, the grandfather of the donor. Marked with Blutstillende Stryphnonwatte... Wein und Klosterneuberg: Pharmazeutische Industrie AG.
    Received from: Prof. J. Horst Meyer, DSc
- Wallace E. Meyers Collection Artifacts, 19th century, 1 items
  Donated by Wallace E. Meyers.
  - Hot water bottle, 19th century (Artifact-box 59, Item hmeyer0001)
    Metal hot water bottle.
    Received from: Wallace E. Meyers
- North Carolina Museum of Science and Art Collection Artifacts, 20th century and undated, approx. 10 items
  Artifacts donated by North Carolina Museum of Science and Art.
  - Pneumothorax apparatus, mid-20th century (Artifact-box 331, Item hncmsa0001)
    Marked: McKesson pneumothor. Toledo, Ohio: McKesson Appliance Co. Model 450; serial no. 1038. Item is housed in case.
    Received from: North Carolina Museum of Science and Art
  - Bone-tip enema syringe, undated (Artifact-box 373, Item hncmsa0002)
    Wooden case - velvet lined. No key.
    Used by Dr. William Studwick of Hillsborough. Given on behalf of the NC Museum of Science & Art by Dr. Thomas Krakauer.
  - Laboratory glassware and wooden stand, undated (Artifact-box 334, Item hncmsa0003, Artifact-box 335, Item hncmsa003)
    Brass handles on each side.
    Given on behalf of the NC Museum of Science & Art by Dr. Thomas Krakauer.
    Artifact Box 334 contains glassware, Artifact Box 335 contains the wooden stand.
- Dr. Elbert C. Persons Collection Artifacts, early 20th century, 1 items
  Artifacts donated by Dr. Elbert C. Persons.
  - Microscope attachment, early 20th century (Artifact-box 372, Item hperso0001)
    Kreuztisch 141 [cross-table] brass microscope attachment. Wetzlar: Ernst Leitz. Item is housed in case.
    Received from: Dr. Elbert C. Persons
- Henry J. Pyle Collection Artifacts, early 20th century
  Artifacts donated by Henry J. Pyle, M.D., Grand Rapids, Michigan
  - Doctor's bag, early 20th century (Artifact-box 369, Item hpyle0001, Artifact-box 370)
    Bag belonged to Henry J. Pyle, M.D., Grand Rapids, Michigan.
- Dr. Bennett Watson Roberts Artifacts, late 19th century - mid-20th century
  Artifacts donated by Snow Roberts.
  - Scale for weighing infants, late 19th century - mid-20th century (Artifact-box 386)
    Scale used for weighing infants, likely produced by the Howe Scale Company. Includes a stand, detachable basin, a notched balancing arm, a hanging pointer, and weights. There are two two-pound weights and two half-pound weights. Dr. Roberts used this scale at Watts Hospital in Durham, where he was a pediatrician.
- Dr. James H. Semans Collection Artifacts, approximately 1860-mid-20th century, approx. 66 items
  Artifacts donated by Dr. James H. Semans.
  - Society of Arts Prize model microscope, approximately 1860 (Artifact-box 49, Item hseman0001)
    Includes a drawer and accessories. [Horne, Thornthwaite and Wood, London?] This all-brass instrument with a claw-footed base is mounted on a wooden stand which was made to slide into its case. Before storage the body-tube would have to have been detached. One of the accessories is a bull's eye condenser lens attached to an adjustable arm which was intended to be inserted through a pillar, allowing it to stand independently of the microscope.
    The original version of this educational microscope was made in 1854 by G. Field of Birmingham.
    Received from: Dr. James H. Semans
  - Cloisonne jar, undated (Artifact-box 219, Item hseman0002)
    Round lidded box with abstract floral patterns.
  - Pocket hypodermic kit, undated (Artifact-box 327, Item hseman0003)
    Contains hypodermic needles and stylets. Engraved silver case.
    Received from: Mrs. Mary D.B.T. Semans
  - Collection of urology instruments for perineal prostatectomy, 20th century (Artifact-box 380, Item hseman0004)
    Instruments were used by Dr. Semans in his practice.
    Contents: anterior perineal retractor for bulbous urethra; posterior perineal retractor for central ligament; two long Allis clips; three long curved Allis clips; suture carriers - two straight and three curved; four long perineal hemostats; urethral sound with attachment for flexible urethral probe (without probe); telescope for oblique lens; MacCarthy urethroscope with obturator; obturator without barrel - small for child; large for adult; syringe (without needle); scissors for transurethral meatotomy; syringe for lavage; Wilford Council transurethral utero-lithotome; urethral guide for urethroscope; rubber tube to force fluid through urethra; catheterizing cystoscope; stylet to keep catheter stiff while threading into urethra; two swabbers to clean cystoscope; MacCarthy transurethral resectoscope; electrical cords for the resectoscope; electric light to illuminate a cavity; attachment for a cystoscope to help hold steady; four cases of cystoscope light bulbs; four lugs for conduct of water; two washers; Luer-lock; four caps; obturator; two valves; catheter guide; five sounds for stretching; phenolsulfaphthaleine (PSP); washer for lavage; glass connector for rubber tubing; metal beads.
- Mary Duke Biddle Trent Semans Collection of Artifacts
  - Bronze mortar with two handles (lacks pestle), undated (Artifact-box 92, Item HMDBTS0001)
  - Bronze mortar and pestle; patterned relief of leaves and silhouettes, undated (Artifact-box 75, Item HMDBTS0002)
  - Bronze mortar and pestle; two small handles; vertical relief, undated (Artifact-box 76, Item HMDBTS0003)
  - Bronze mortar and pestle; patterned relief of silhouettes, undated (Artifact-box 77, Item HMDBTS0004)
  - Bronze mortar and pestle; patterned relief of leaves and other design, undated (Artifact-box 74, Item HMDBTS0005)
  - Monaural stethoscope with ivory ear and bell piece, undated (Artifact-box 127, Item HMDBTS0006)
    Inscription on stethoscope: Dr. Scott 369 Grand N. Exeter Hall. Flexible monaural stethoscopes were introduced around 1832. These were tubes of coiled spring covered with woven silk, usually 14 to 18 inches long, with a chest piece at one end and usually a very short, straight earpiece at the other.
  - 19th century (?) chain saw for bone resection with metal handles, undated (Artifact-box 126, Item HMDBTS0007)
  - Two glass vials with spouts, undated (Artifact-box 99, Item HMDBTS0008)
  - Bone- or ivory-handled dental key (one hook), undated (Artifact-box 122, Item HMDBTS0009)
  - Large metal ear trumpet, undated (Artifact-box 90, Item HMDBTS0010)
  - Brass scarficator in case, undated (Artifact-box 171, Item HMDBTS0011)
    Scarifcator has 12 blades; no other markings on scarifcator or box.
  - Circumcision knife and shield in leather case (Muneles & Inwald Juveline Prag?), undated (Artifact-box 128, Item HMDBTS0012)
  - Green tinted glass bottle (Amer 33/ 1820) (Artifact-box 101, Item HMDBTS0013)
  - 19th century nursing bottle, undated (Artifact-box 121, Item HMDBTS0014)
  - Early American nursing bottle, 1790? (Artifact-box 100, Item HMDBTS0015)
  - Early American nursing bottle, 1800 (Artifact-box 118, Item HMDBTS0016)
  - Blue tinted eyeglasses in leather case, undated (Artifact-box 96, Item HMDBTS0017)
    Case stamped A.H. Kennedy 246 N. Second St. Philadelphia.
  - Tortoise shell case with two lancets, undated (Artifact-box 168, Item HMDBTS0018)
  - Small leather case of ivory handled dissecting instruments, undated (Artifact-box 87, Item HMDBTS0019)
    Seven small ivory handled tools; top case lowers to reveal two more tools (red velvet lined case); 11 instruments total. Label in case says "Dissecting instruments of the best quality, manufactured by P. Madeira Eight Street, two doors below Chestnut, Philadelphia".
  - Small red leather case with ivory handled dental tools, undated (Artifact-box 95, Item HMDBTS0020)
    Red leather case; blue velvet interior. 8 pieces total.
  - Metal tin with brass scales, undated (Artifact-box 89, Item HMDBTS0021)
    Outer lid of tin has bird; inside is bright orange; small mss included w/ wts?
  - One pair of round eyeglasses, undated (Artifact-box 94, Item HMDBTS0022)
  - Unknown ivory? handled tool (damaged), undated (Artifact-box 123, Item HMDBTS0023)
  - Circumcision knife in brown leather stamped/tooled case, undated (Artifact-box 124, Item HMDBTS0024)
    Outer case elaborately stamped; inside has green lining; knife with gold / glass handle.
  - Double brass? medicine spoon, undated (Artifact-box 97, Item HMDBTS0025)
  - Sterling Silver Chatelaine Glasses Case with glasses, undated (Artifact-box 120, Item HMDBTS0026)
    Back of case is leather - has small metal chain and clip.
  - Spring lancet in green leather case, undated (Artifact-box 170, Item HMDBTS0027)
    Inscribed Wiegand & Snowden.
  - Ivory handled ophthalmoscope, undated (Artifact-box 172, Item HMDBTS0028)
    No marking or inscription, only "35" on the back.
  - Small metal syringe, undated (Artifact-box 98, Item HMDBTS0029)
  - Knife in wooden box, undated (Artifact-box 91, Item HMDBTS0030)
  - Small surgical/bloodletting tool set in folding leather case, undated (Artifact-box 88, Item HMDBTS0031)
    Includes tweezers, tortoise shield lancets, scissors, catheter. Otto & Reynders Surg Inst Trusses 64 Chatam St NY.
  - Hammer with wooden handle, undated (Artifact-box 93, Item HMDBTS0032)
  - "Craftsman" saw, undated (Artifact-box 86, Item HMDBTS0033)
  - 16 blade brass square scarificator, undated (Artifact-box 125, Item HMDBTS0034)
  - Sterling Silver Chatelaine Glasses Case with glasses, undated (Artifact-box 131, Item HMDBTS0035)
  - Spring lancet in brown leather case, undated (Artifact-box 102, Item HMDBTS0036)
  - 3 blade brass fleam in leather case, undated (Artifact-box 169, Item HMDBTS0037)
  - Perkins tractors, late 18th century (Artifact-box 119, Item HMDBTS0038)
    Elisha Perkins (1741-99) of CT claimed to draw out pains from any part of the body using this pair of metal rods (one silver, one brass).
  - Asian medicine doll, undated (Artifact-box 79, Item HMDBTS0039)
- Robert W. Severence Collection Artifacts, 1930s, 2 items
  Artifacts donated by Robert W. Severence.
  - Sphygmomanometer and stethoscope, 1930s (Artifact-box 158, Item hsever0001)
    Sphygmomanometer is a baumanometer. New York: W.A. Baum Co. Engraved plate on cover with Dr. Easley's name.
    Received from: Robert W. Severance
- Dr. D.J. Smith Collection Artifacts, undated, 2 items
  Artifacts donated by Dr. D.J. Smith.
  - Fused glass specimen, undated (Artifact-box 339, Item hsmith0001)
    Housed in wooden box made for shipping this item.
    Unknown material, possibly silica glass. One common way in which lechatelierite forms naturally is by very high temperature melting of quartz sand during a lightning strike. Lechatelierite may also form artificially, a unique example being the trinitite produced by melting of quartz sand at the first nuclear bomb explosion at Trinity Flats, White Sands, New Mexico.
    Received from: Dr. D.J. Smith
- Dr. W.W. Stanfield Collection Artifacts, undated, 5 items
  Artifacts donated by Dr. W.W. Stanfield.
  - Bleeding bowl, undated (Artifact-box 68, Item hstanf0001)
    Received from: Dr. W.W. Stanfield of Dunn, NC
  - Scarificator (Artifact-box 253, Item hstanf0002)
    Single blade scarificator in leather case, undated
  - Brass mortar and pestle, undated (Artifact-box 241, Item hstanf0003)
    Brass mortar and pestle
- Dr. Haywood M. Taylor Collection Artifacts, approximately 1900, approx. 10 items
  Artifacts donated by Dr. and Mrs. Haywood M. Taylor.
  - Medicine chest, approximately 1900 (Artifact-box 276, Item htaylo0001)
    Portable medicine chest, Philadelphia, Lentz & Sons, Co. Comes in leather case with shoulder strap. Filled with empty pharmacy jars (no content, no labels).
    Engraved metal plate on cover identifies original owner as H.E. Fernold, M.D. The donor, Dr. Taylor, was a member of the original staff of Duke Hospital.
    Received from: Dr. and Mrs. Haywood M. Taylor
- Dr. Josiah Charles Trent Collection Artifacts, approximately 1650-late 19th century, over 50 items
  Access Restrictions
  Some of these items may be on display or are fragile, and require advance notice to view. Please contact the History of Medicine Collections Curator directly before coming to use this collection.
  Artifacts donated by Dr. Josiah Charles Trent.
  - R. & J. Beck Compound binocular microscope, mid-19th century (Artifact-box 165, Item htrent0001)